Learn to build and publish a real Instagram style mobile app from scratch using Codex and GPT-6 Astra.
Brock will guide you through the complete development lifecycle, covering everything from generating UI designs and setting up a backend
to App Store deployment.
You'll master not just the code, but the exact AI prompting workflows needed to turn an idea into a finished product.
Welcome to the complete codex tutorial on how to build a real mobile application using AI.
In this course, I'm going to show you the exact workflow that I use to go from an idea all the way to a working mobile application.
And just for some context, recently I have used this exact same workflow to build my own mobile application and publish it to the App Store.
So everything I'm gonna show you in this video actually works. Just before we jump into coding, let me show you the project that we're gonna build in this tutorial.
So this is a social media application, just like Instagram.
If you want to use it, first you need to be authenticated.
And here in our case we have two different options.
I'll go ahead and log in with my Google account.
So once you're authenticated, you'll be redirected to the home screen.
And here we have four different tabs, which are home, messages, explore, and profile.
And notice how we have the iOS liquid glass effect, and I'm going to show you how to build it without writing too much code.
And now in the home screen you can see the posts of the user that you already follow.
And here you can also post stories.
So let's go ahead and select something from our library.
If you wanted to, you can also get it from your camera.
But here I'll just select something from the library.
So I'll go ahead and maybe post this image.
Let's publish.
This is going to upload it in the background, and once it is done, we will be able to view it.
So here
here we go.
So the stories works just like in Instagram. If you want to pause it, you can tap and hold it.
And if you want to go to the next one, you would just press.
And you can delete your stories if you are the owner.
Now we can also post
posts, right? So you can create posts. Let's go ahead and publish something.
I'll select this image and we can add a caption. Let's just say this weekend trip
and let's post it.
So here we go, it's posted, and we can see it immediately in the home screen.
You can like it and you can even add comments.
So let's go ahead and just say something like I don't know, something test
and post it. Now it's gonna be right here.
You can like the comments, you can sort them. Here we have a couple of different options, and you can even bookmark the posts.
So that's it for the home screen. We also have real time messages.
So here you can tell we have a couple of different past chats, but they are all fake data that I created for the sake of this demo.
Here I'm gonna put the actual footage from the tutorial where I actually test this out from my phone. So I literally sent a message in real time, and everything works in both of these accounts.
And other than messages, we have the explore screen where you can see random posts from other people with a really good UI design.
You can like them, and if you press them, that's gonna take you to the actual post.
And from here you'll be able to see the other accounts and follow them or even unfollow them if you already follow.
Here you can search for people, posts, or even topics.
Then eventually we have the profile screen where you can see your posts, even videos, bookmarks, and the tagged
posts.
So you can also edit your profile here. Let's just say For the bio I'll put something like I don't know let's put
YouTuber and then I'll save.
As soon as I save, here you can tell profile has been updated.
On top of this, you can also change the profile image and we have the settings screen.
Now here we have a bunch of different buttons and links, but the most important ones are the privacy policy and terms of services.
Here you can tell we actually link it with a real
URL and we link it right here. Now this is something that you must implement.
If you don't implement it, Apple will reject your application, and I'm gonna teach you how to do it later in the course.
Then we also have the delete account option. Again, this is one of those things that if you don't implement your application will get rejected.
And we even have a feedback button where users can literally send us some feedback.
Like here they can put their name.
I already filled this in, but you know, you can just put John, your email, and then if you want to have a feature request or I don't know, any kind of bugs, here
you can tell, you know, please fix the edit profile feature.
It doesn't work. And then you can send the feedback, and I'm gonna show you how you can collect those feedbacks later in the video.
Now on top of the mobile application, we're gonna build a landing page with a really nice looking UI design.
Here you can tell we have some demo images, and I'm gonna show you how to create them and use them for your future projects.
And at the very bottom, we have the privacy policy and terms of services links.
Again, these are the things that you don't really want to skip.
So that's the entire project that we're gonna build in this video.
Now, this is not one of those random vibe coding tutorials where we just open Codex and say, build me an application and hope everything somehow works.
Instead, I'm gonna show you the entire process step by step. We are gonna start with an idea, then we will plan the application properly, figure out all the features that we would need,
generate a complete UI design, and then use codecs to actually implement everything.
By the end of this tutorial, you should have a clear understanding of all the tools that you would need to build a modern application using AI.
You will also know what to do when you get stuck, because one of the biggest problems when you're coding with AI is not necessarily the coding itself.
It is knowing what to ask. So throughout this course, I'll show you how I deal with it, how I give codecs more context, and how I get it actually help me solve the problem.
I will also share the prompts that I personally use.
This includes the prompts that I use for planning an application, generating the UI design, implementing the screens, and even creating things like privacy policy and terms of services.
And these things are actually important if you want to publish your app.
Depending on what your application does and what kind of user data that you're collecting, Apple can require things like a privacy policy,
terms of service, delete account feature, and other information.
If you miss something that is required for your application, you can easily get rejected during the app store review.
These are usually the things you would learn the hard way after building your first application.
But I'll try to cover all of them in this tutorial so you know what to look out for before you submit your application.
It is also important to mention that when people submit their application to the app store, for the first couple of times they get rejected,
which is normal, but in my case I never got rejected by Apple.
My app literally got accepted in the first submission because this workflow covers everything so you don't really miss any important detail.
And just one more thing that all the tools that we're gonna use in this course are completely free to get started with.
So you don't need a credit card to follow along, and the complete source code for the application will also be available for free. I will leave the link in the description.
My goal with this course is helping you to understand the entire workflow so that after finishing this video,
you can take your own idea and actually know how to turn it into a real mobile application using Codex.
So we're gonna go from idea to planning to UI design and finally getting the app ready to publish.
Now, with all that being said, let's not waste any time and get started with the course.
Now, just before we get started, I quickly want to mention that we have a school community.
And within the school community, I have basically documented the entire journey of building my own application and publishing it to
App Store. Here you can tell everything took exactly 14 days because day zero is kind of like crash course. So everything took around 14 days to submit it to the App Store.
And then we start with marketing and new classes will be coming every single day.
So this is a community for those of you that are interested to see the entire process, like having payments. You know, we have monthly, yearly plans, maybe even some weekly plans.
Then how do you get through the entire submission process?
Or something like how to implement push notifications.
And this is not just a course, but it's a live community. Here you can tell everyone is sharing their own process, like motivating each other, so on and so forth.
And actually, one of our students has already published their app on the app store. And just for the record, this is his app and he built it with me within our community in exactly 14 days.
And just to give you some insights, like when you press one of these classes, we have specific videos for that day.
And you can always come back and double check these lessons if you're interested. So if you want to join, I'm going to leave the link in the description and hopefully I'll see you inside.
Alright, so as usual, we are gonna start from absolute scratch.
First off, in my case, I'm using VS Code as my code editor, but you can really use anything that you want.
That could be cursor, I don't know, it could be windsurf, really anything that you wish.
But I would recommend you to use VS Code so that we have the exact same environment.
Now for this you can visit code visualstudio.com and then press this button.
Now in my case I'm using Mac, but if you're on Windows, you're gonna see a related button and you can just install it for Windows as well.
And once again, in this tutorial I'm using Mac, but if you're using Windows, everything will be almost exactly the same.
So you can follow along without any issues.
The other thing that you must have is Node.js.
If you don't have it already, just visit Node.js.org, press the download button, leave everything as it is.
Like by default, it's gonna select your environment, you know, your operating system, and then install it.
Okay, so I'll just assume that you have both of them, then head over to your desktop, create an empty folder.
In my case, I call this as CodexGram, which is like Instagram, but I put codex, You can call this anything that you wish,
and then just open it up in VS Code.
So basically just drag and drop it right here, it's going to open this up. Okay, so once you have it, now we can start building a mobile application.
Now, what I'll be doing is first creating a boilerplate.
And for this, we'll be using Expo.
So if you don't know already, let's go ahead and visit expo.dev.
This is literally the best way to start a mobile application as of 2026. Literally, they have everything that you would need from building the app to publishing it to App Store and Play Store.
This is what I used to build and publish my app to App Store, you know, just to let you know.
And this is completely free to get started with.
But if you're serious about publishing your app to the app store, then probably you would like to go with at least $20 per month plan.
Uh but yeah, for now we don't really need to pay anything at all. Now with this, um, we'll go ahead and visit expo.dev slash docs, which is the documentation, and we need to copy this command.
Now technically we can just ask cloud or codex to run this for us, but here I'd like to run it manually to show you what we're going to
get.
And like it's going to be a little bit easier to do it by ourselves.
So paste this in to your terminal and put dot at the end, which means create an expo application under the current folder, right?
This is what that means.
So it's going to create everything right here.
First, we are gonna get a question.
At the time that I'm recording this video, it is SDK57.
But if you're watching it in the future, this will be incremented.
That's not a problem at all. Just go ahead and press enter.
And this will get a couple of different files and folders, which is basically a simple mobile application.
And we can run it in a simulator just in a second, once this is completed.
Now I am on Mac, my simulator is going to be an iOS simulator. But if you're on Windows, you can install an Android simulator, right?
So here I'll go ahead and run my simulator.
And by the way, with the latest features, like as of now that I'm recording the video, with Expo, you can be on Windows,
but still build it for iOS.
Like you can literally run an iOS simulator on Windows.
Just check their documentation.
Um you'll be able to see it. It is pretty new, so I'm not going to get into it, but just know that something like that existed.
Okay, so here I have my simulator. I have some previous projects that I created in the past, but we are going to go ahead and start from scratch.
So here it says you can start this app by running these commands for Android, iOS, and even for web.
Here I'll go ahead and just say npx expo or npx expo start. This will give us a QR code as well as a open terminal where if you press i it is going to open this app
in your simulator.
So let me actually put them side by side.
Okay, so it looks like something has failed. I'll press i once again.
It is trying to open this.
I don't know why I'm getting an error, usually it should open it immediately.
But now that's not a problem at all. I'll just go ahead and you know ask cloud or codex to explain what is happening here.
And speaking of cloud and codex, if you'd like to use cloud,
you need to install this extension within the VS Code.
So cloud code for VS Code and make sure you get the verified one. And then if you'd like to use Codex, this is what I'll be doing in this tutorial.
Even though I have subscription for both of them, Codex has a recent model called GPT6 Astra, and I'd like to use it in this tutorial.
So go ahead and get Codex if you have subscription or cloud or really anything that you wanted to have.
And by the way, one thing that I want to mention is that the goal of this tutorial is not getting the exact same end result.
So the goal here is understanding the workflow to build mobile apps by yourself.
So it's fine if at the end of this video you have a different app than what I have.
I mean the functionalities will probably be the same, but UI design could be different, code could be a bit different, and that's because AI doesn't really give the exact same end
result every single time.
Okay, so that's one thing to keep in mind. It's completely fine if you don't have the exact same end result that I have right here.
And other than this, like I see a lot of people get kind of like depressed because of AI, where it can almost build anything. now.
but I've been always like, I've always been on this side where I'm just trying to find the opportunity where, you know.
it helps me to build an app pretty quickly so that I can focus on marketing and, you know, focus on different things.
Now, since AI can build anything, which is not really true at the moment, even though I think it's gonna be at some point,
but at the moment it's not really true, it cannot build anything, it can build something to start with, but as the projects get larger and larger,
it kinda sucks.
So I think it's still important to know the fundamentals of programming.
But if you wanted to build a simple project, I don't know, an MVP, I think AI can help.
And with this tutorial, hopefully you will learn how to build an MVP.
Okay, so with that said, I would definitely recommend you to get a $20 a month plan in one of these, either Cloud, Codex,
or Cursor. I think for now my favorite could be Codex, even though I've been using Cloud for a very long time, with the latest model they have,
which is GPT6. I think you can go with Codex just to test this out. And I think Codex is cheaper than Cloud or Cursor.
Okay, so with that said, now let's jump back into VS Code.
Go ahead and get this extension.
And I think I need to restart the extension.
And you'll just press twice to this empty area.
From here, you can get cloud or codex.
Let's say you're using cloud.
This is the interface that you will have. Now you can talk with cloud. And you can, you know, update the model.
Let me actually maximize this.
Like you can update the mode
and initially we'll use the plan mode. I'm gonna get into that.
and you can update the model.
You know, we can add the effort, etc.
And we have similar thing for codecs.
This is what I'll be using.
So just go ahead and press that.
Now here you can again change the model.
The latest one at the time that I'm recording this video is this one, and you can update the effort as well.
So here I'll just give the full access so that I don't really get um.
So one thing I want to mention is that here the extra high and even like ultra you go is better,
but it's going to be taking much more time than it should.
So here usually I would go with medium or high if I'm building something, a feature that is not really that important.
But if I'm trying to build something that should work exactly as I want, then I would probably go with extra high or even ultra,
but just know that it will take much more time if you go with one of these.
So in this tutorial, I think to start with, I'll go with medium, and here for the permissions, I'll just give the full access so that it doesn't really ask me questions all the time.
So here I basically say, Hey codex, whatever you would like to do, just do it, don't ask me.
just be careful with it, but usually you'll just give the full access, anyways.
Okay, now to start with,
first thing I'll be doing is opening up my terminal with Ctrl J.
And I think now application is running.
We had an error, but it just fixed
by itself.
Here you can tell if you press R, it's going to reload the app, and we have this default project coming from Expo.
Now, of course, we're going to delete everything and let's actually do it.
You would like to open up your terminal, so kill this with CtrlC, clear this up, and there is a command that we can run.
So it's going to be npm run reset dash project.
This is going to basically take all these folders and files that we don't really need, and it's going to delete them.
So now we have some components that we don't really need, some constants, hooks, so on and so forth.
So just go ahead and run this, then press enter once again.
Here you can tell everything has been deleted and it has put it under an example folder, which I don't really need, so I'm going to delete that one as well.
Now let's run this app with npx expo.
This is what we had initially, right?
Now if you press R, it's going to reload it.
And notice how we have much more simpler application, right? This is literally just one screen with a simple text.
Okay.
Now with this in mind, let's go ahead and plan a project.
And in this tutorial, I would like to use sorry, I'd like to build a social media application.
Kind of like Instagram, but of course much more simpler than that.
Alright, so I have accidentally paused the video, but I was just saying that we would like to build an Instagram clone that is much more simpler,
right?
So we'll have maybe things like posting photos, commenting, having a profile screen, things like that.
and here's the workflow that we're going to be using. This is what I used to build my own mobile application as well.
And I'll try to break it down as we go through this course.
So the very first thing that you need to do is planning your project.
This is a step that a lot of beginners just skip.
They immediately jump into coding because they're like really excited, but it almost always fails because if you don't plan everything,
then at some point AI will start guessing, even like at the start.
So what you'd like to do is kind of like giving the AI the context, what kind of project that you would like to have, you know, like define your idea,
goals, features, pages, user flow, and text stack so that it doesn't really guess all these tools and features.
And for this, I have a really, really good prompt that is working every single time. So I'm gonna leave this in the description.
Just go ahead and copy this entire thing and you can pause the video and read it.
Basically, I'll try to simplify it.
We ask AI to interview us about every single thing about this project so that it doesn't really guess anything, and we are on the same page.
Okay, so once again, you can treat this entire thing if you're interested.
But I'm just gonna copy this and go into cloud, sorry, into VS Code and into Codex.
Here you would like to select the mode.
Let me find it.
It should be a plan mode.
And to select plan mode you need to press this plus and then go ahead press the plan mode.
Now paste the prompt first, and then here we say we are about to describe you the project.
And here now I'll just go ahead and explain everything.
Once I have it, I'll just be right back.
So here I have paused the video and tried to explain it to Codex, and here is my entire prompt.
So here I said I want to build a simple Instagram style social media application using clerk for authentication and convex for the backend
and database.
I'm gonna get into both of these technologies, but basically this is the text tag to get started with. And then here I said users should be able to sign up and log in with Google or Apple.
They should be able to create images or videos as posts, follow and unfollow, you know, like and comment, you can read the rest. And there is also sending direct messages, right?
And they can also view and edit their profile.
And here I say the app should have four main tabs, which are gonna be home, messages, explore, and profile.
Now talking about tabs, let's go ahead and take a look at the native tabs in Expo.
I'll just say native tabs and visit it in the expo documentation.
Just scroll to the bottom. So these are the tabs.
This is what I mean by tabs, and native tabs are giving this iOS liquid glass effect.
Okay, so you don't really need to restyle it or generate it from scratch.
There is a component called native tabs, and it's gonna give you all these features out of the box.
If you're interested, you can take a look at the entire documentation, but this is something that we would like to use. And here, let's actually also say
Something like we will use native tabs
and also for styling, let's say
we want to use something like native wind.
So native wind is basically Tailwind CSS but for React Native, okay, for mobile application.
Okay, so you got the point.
First off, you're gonna get the plan prompt from right here, right?
And then you would like to describe your project.
Um, this is exactly what I have done. Of course, this should be a lot more detailed if you can, but for this demo purposes, I think that's fine. And here we'll go ahead and run this.
This will ask a couple of different questions in like a couple of different batches.
First, you are gonna get maybe like four questions, we'll answer all of them, and then we're gonna get another batch of four, and then another one
until AI has every single thing, the entire context.
Once we have it, plan will be ready.
Then we can actually start building the project.
And instead of building immediately, what I'd like to do is generating the UI design depending on that plan that we generated.
And I'm gonna get into that again. I'll give you some prompts to generate the UI design.
Okay, so I am back in VS Code.
Here we got the very first batch of questions. We have three different questions. Here it says who is V14 and what counts as a successful first release.
Now, most of the time you'd like to go with the recommended answer, but there will be some places where you'd like to actually choose
different like different answers than recommended, and even sometimes add your own description.
But in this case, I'll just say this should be just a working demo, and I'll go with the recommended option.
Then here it says, like, should we build it for both iOS and Android? Here I only want to have it for iOS first, so I'm gonna say, you know, like just go ahead and select this option.
If you wanted to, you can select this one as well, but this is the one that I'll have.
And then let's say public to members. Yes, everyone should be able to use it as long as they are signed in.
Okay, so now AI will keep these answers in memory, and then it's gonna ask us another batch of questions.
So I think I'll just go through and answer every single one of them.
Once it is done, I'll just be right back.
And instead of answering them off camera, here I'll just do it right here so that you can see the type of questions that I'm getting.
For image creations, let's just say single upload only so that we can keep it simple.
So here it says what users should see once they sign up. We'll say they have to choose a username.
And then here I'll just say home header button.
What comment and deletion behavior do you want for the demo?
Let's just have flat comments and own deletion.
You can go a lot more complex, but for the initial version, that's not really what you would like to do.
So here again, you can read the question. This will be my answer.
And then it says what media limits are acceptable for this demo.
Let's just say images up to 10 megabytes and video up to 30 seconds and 50 megabytes. We don't really want to allow too large images and videos at the start.
Um, here it says can V1 exclude push notifications? Yeah, absolutely. We don't really want to have payments, push notifications for initial version. I'll just say yes, trust the demo.
We don't really want to build something really complex from the start.
And this is what I have done with my own mobile app as well. Like instead of building every single feature from the start, I basically started with the simple version, which is v1,
right? Just an MVP.
So I said at least users should be able to take a photo and calculate their calories with AI.
Once I had it, then I added a bunch of more features, right?
You don't really want to build everything from the start.
From my experience, this has been working really nice, and this is what I would recommend.
I would say.
Um, here we'll just say we would like to build our own custom native screen instead of using the clerk UI, because I'd like to show you how to generate something from the UI design that we're going to
get from AI.
Okay, so I'll go with this option.
And we would like to use convex throughout the project.
Let's say online first, and there should be free tries as well.
So here I have another question about the theme.
Instead of answering any of these, like I'll just put my own kind of like description, or I'll just try to explain something like for now
only light mode, and I'm gonna say for colors, I'll provide a design reference
later at some point.
Because we don't really want it to use some you know, like a color palette, like blue it says, but I don't really want to have it later. At some point, I'll provide a pre-made design.
So I'll just say use that one.
So let's say it should be tap to play, I think. Yeah, it is recommended. I'll just go with this one.
Now there is something called development build, and let me try to explain pretty quickly before I answer this. So here you can tell we are running our application, right?
But it is within the Expo Go.
So this is the tool that expo provides you, but this is for testing purposes, right? This is for learning purposes.
When you're building an actual application, then you would like to create a development build.
Because within this, you cannot really have every single feature or some native modules doesn't really run within the expo go.
Okay, so once again, in simple terms, this is for testing purposes for learning demos. If you want to build a real project, then you'd like to use something called development build.
And basically what this does in simple terms is that it's gonna take your application, right?
And instead of running it within the Expo Go, it'll create this kind of a standalone application, okay?
And we're gonna see it.
I know that this sounds confusing for the first time for beginners, but I think that's completely fine. We'll see how that works.
So you would like to use a development build if you are building a real project.
So that's how I can explain it in simple terms.
So we have more questions, I'll just go ahead and choose the recommended ones.
So that we don't really waste too much time.
But I think you're able to see the workflow. You'll have all these questions so that AI doesn't really guess any feature, but instead, you are the one that deciding all of these.
Now, here it says, What should a brand new user see when they follow no one?
So basically, when you sign up for the first time, you know, you are not following anyone.
And what you what should you see on the screen?
So here you can go with the empty state. I'll just say seeded demo content, which means basically add some you know fake content or you know test accounts so that they can see some posts.
I think this is gonna be better, especially for this tutorial.
If I was building this as a real project, I would probably go with the honest empty states.
But here I'm going to select this one, and here it says, should messages include unread indicators?
Um I think for now I'll just leave it as a bare chat list.
Maybe at some point we can add these features. But for now I'll just leave it simple and choose this option.
And here it says, will you able to?
So this is the other question that I just got, and this will be my answer.
Here I'll say for now we will just use the clerk authentication with public key.
And this is something that we're gonna get into.
Basically, clerk will give you an environment variable, and it's gonna be our public key that we can use in development.
I'll go ahead and submit this as well.
Off camera, I have answered some more questions, and here's the entire thing.
We can pause the video and read it. If you are building a real project, this is exactly what I would do.
And here now it says, ready for me to turn this into an implementation plan.
Here I'll just say for now, go ahead and create this under a file, a markdown file called plan.md, kind of like readme.md, but here I should be able to at least see it.
So here I'll just say for now, create a plan.md file with all the
details
so that later we can,
you know, implement this step by step.
So I'm gonna run this, it'll create that plan.md file.
And after this, I'm gonna leave this lesson right here.
In the next lesson, we're gonna get started with the UI design.
And for this, once again, I'll provide a prompt that will help us to generate really nice looking UI designs.
And once we have the design, then we'll go into codecs and we're gonna break it into features.
Like first, we're gonna build the authentication, and then you know, let's say the database connection, so on and so forth. And I'm gonna get into that in the next lesson.
For now, let's just wait for this to create the plan.
So here it says this is the entire plan, it is trying to still write it.
Once it is done, I believe we're gonna get that plan.md file.
Alright, so here we have the entire plan.
You can take a look at it. you'll also have your own plan.
Here it says, Do you want me to implement this?
And I say for now, only create the file.
Later I'll ask for implementation.
So here turns out it can create the plan.md while we are in the plan mode.
So here it says just deactivate it.
If you press this, plan mode is gone.
And here I'll just say I
or I'll just say do it now.
So within the next two minutes, it has created the plan.md with the entire details.
You will have the exact same thing depending on the context that you give in to AI.
Okay, so I think we can end this section right here.
But just before we do so, what I'd like to do is committing everything and publishing it to GitHub.
Now I'm gonna go ahead and close this.
If you wanted to, you can ask AI to do it for you, but for the first time, I'll just do it manually.
Here, first off, let's go into GitHub.
If you don't have an account, go ahead and create one.
It's completely free to get started with, and then just press new, create a new repository.
Then you will be on the screen.
You need to give it a name.
Here in my case, I think I'll go with something like So I think I'll go with this name, and for now I'm gonna make it private, but at the time that you're watching this video, it's gonna be public
and free, but for now we'll go with the private.
Yeah, other than this, you can leave everything as it is and create the repository.
Now it's gonna give us a command, which is this part.
We're gonna copy it and paste it into our terminal.
So I'm gonna first copy this and go into VS Code.
First, I'm gonna stage everything.
So under this tab,
press this button where it says stage all the changes, and then let's create a commit message by pressing this button.
So AI will create the message.
Technically, you can type anything, but it does just better to use this feature of AI.
And now we're gonna commit this. And let's try to publish the branch, I would say, but first we need to, I think, go into our terminal, kill this,
clear this up, and then paste this in that we just copied.
Now, what this does is basically taking all these local changes that we have in our laptop, in our machine, and push it to the
to the repo that we just created.
So notice how once this is done successfully, you'll be able to reload this and see everything.
Like they are literally right here.
Okay, so we had all these local changes, they are now live on GitHub.
Okay, so I think I'm gonna leave this lesson right here.
Remember, this is one of the most important steps when you're building an application. So I think you should spend a lot of time while planning your application.
So instead of just jumping into coding immediately, you should you should spend a lot of time and talk with AI just like what we have done in this lesson.
Okay, so with this, I'm gonna see you in the next lesson where we will generate the UI design.
Alright, so this is where we left. In the previous lesson, we have planned our project. Now it is time to get started with the UI design.
Now for this, I already have a bunch of different prompts that I used that give me really, really nice looking designs.
And now we're gonna use a similar thing.
So here we have one design for AI trip planner application, we have another one for recipe app, and this is the prompt that I used to get that design.
Same thing for a dating app, then the actual UI design for my mobile application, and then at the end for the dental
application UI design.
You can find this link in the description. I'm gonna leave it. Um let's scroll to the top.
And basically, I'm gonna copy this entire prompt, but now remember this is for the trip planner application, but we are building for something like a social media application.
So what we'll be doing is first copying this prompt, going into Chat GPT or Gemini, whatever you're using, paste the prompt, and then we'll say
depending on our plan, which is right here, so copy it, we'll say depending on our plan, give us a prompt like this one.
And once we have the prompt, we'll paste it into a new chat that will generate the image for us.
So I'm going to go ahead, paste this in, which is my plan,
and then here I can say something like
depending on the plan that I have, I want you to generate me a prompt like this that will generate a UI design.
Okay.
Once again, basically it's gonna read our plan, and depending on the plan, it will give us a prompt like this so that we can go into a new chat and generate an image.
And there is a new model that GPT just released, which is image 2.5.
It looks really really nice. I already tried this out.
let's just say create image, and then once we have the prompt, I'm gonna copy it and paste it. But looks like this is trying to generate the image.
Well, not really, it wasn't an image, so it was a prompt, just like what we asked. So I'm gonna go ahead and copy this entire thing,
like up until here, and I'm gonna paste it right here.
Alright, so after some time, this is the end result that I got from GPT.
I think the UI itself is looking pretty clean and crisp, but there are a couple of different things that I didn't really like, which is the icon.
So here instead I'd like to have a camera icon.
And I will also say that you know this is the design system. I wanted to upscale it.
here's my prompt.
You can do a similar thing. So I said this is a good start, but I want you to update the logo from the CO letter to a camera icon, similar to Instagram, but a little bit different.
So do not copy it exactly.
Also upscale the design system as a separate image.
So I'm gonna go ahead and run this now.
Once we have the design system, we'll go into VS Code.
Let's create a folder called design, and within this, we're gonna have the design system, we'll attach it, and we will also have
each of these screens upscaled one by one. So this is my workflow, let me show you that.
So we will generate the full UI design, which is kind of like what we have done right here, right?
And then we're gonna upscale each screen, like one screen at a time. Let's say first we will upscale the authentication, and then I don't know, like the onboarding profile, so on and so forth.
And we are going to build them one by one.
I think we can start with the authentication screen, and I believe
right here we should have the Oath screen. Let me try to zoom in.
Yeah, but like this doesn't really good, uh, this doesn't really look that good. I think this text is unnecessary, but
yeah, like we'll just try to follow up with GPT a couple of more times until we get something that we actually like.
Now, this is the thing about AI, most people just try to get the best result in the first shot, and if they don't get it, they kind of like give up.
They're like, AI sucks, it's not really good, but dude, like it's just AI at the end of the day.
You need to follow up a couple of more times, give it a reference, you know, so you can get something that you actually like.
In this case, I didn't really like the authentication screen design, so I'm gonna follow up in a second.
all right so after some time, this is the image that I got.
Here you can tell the logo has been updated, and then I think we also have the design system, which is kind of like upscaled.
So we can copy this and paste it into VS Code in a second, but here I think, you know, as I already told you, I didn't like the authentication UI screen.
So here you can tell this is my prompt. I just said give me a different variation and upscale that image, also upscale the design system.
So for some reason, initially I didn't see this one.
but yeah, I'm gonna go ahead and copy this image and I'll paste it right here.
And let's just say design system reference.
Now the reason that we generated this and also the entire design is because like
our AI agent can take a look at it and see all the components, all the colors, like fonts, literally everything that it needs.
Because here it's going to be harder to find it, and it doesn't really include everything.
And now I'm going to copy this image as well.
Let's go into VS Code, I'm going to paste it right here, and let's say this is the Oath screen design,
or you can just say reference as well.
This is what I usually like to call it. Now, with this, we can literally go ahead and ask AI to build this design, and for this, again, I have a kind of like a special loop that I'm going to
show you in the incoming minutes, but for now that's the authentication screen.
After authentication, what we can create, let's take a look at it.
Um we can create the profile screen or the home screen, but for now I'm just gonna copy this entire image.
So I was just saying that I'm gonna copy this image and I'll go into VS Code.
Right here, I'm gonna paste this and I'll say the design reference, or let's just say app design reference.
Okay.
Now this is the entire design, right?
This is the design system and this is the authentication screen.
Anytime that we want to build one screen at a time, we'll be using you know this kind of images.
We are going to upscale every single screen.
Now we might be asking how can we get this demo image so that we can use it in the authentication screen?
Well, that's a nice question. What I'll be doing is going into GPT and I'll say
I want you to generate me the demo image that you're using in the authentication screen.
Okay, so it's going to generate that image so we can use it later in the authentication screen.
So I don't know why, but initially it has generated this image, which is something that I don't really like, because this is what we'd like to use in the authentication screen.
So I took this screenshot.
If you're on Mac, it's gonna be command shift control and for.
Okay, so command control shift and for is going to allow you to take the screenshot
and then just paste it right here.
So I said I I meant this one, and then I also said, you know, make the background to be transparent so that it matches the white background of the application.
Okay, so basically we don't really want to have this background on the image.
So this is the end result that I got.
I'm just going to copy it and paste it right here.
Let's actually put it under the assets images,
control V
and let's say Oath demo image.
Later in the video, we'll be using it and I'll show you how to attach it to the codex chat.
Okay, so that's my design workflow in simple terms.
Now I could have made this a lot longer than this. I can explain every single detail, like how we can create every single screen, how we can upscale them, but that's really the basic gist of it.
Now you need to do the same thing over and over again to generate all these images, and actually, like later in the video,
you're gonna see that we don't really need to create all of them at some point, because we're gonna have enough design references, and Cloud
will be able to build the other screens just by looking at this image.
Okay, so with this in mind, I think I'm gonna end this section right here.
This has been like 10 minute lesson, I believe, or something like that, 10 to 15 minutes.
I'm gonna go ahead and stage everything.
We only have some images, and we're gonna say get a commit message.
Once we have the commit message, we're gonna go ahead and commit and we're gonna say sync this up.
Basically, it's gonna take these local changes and push it to our GitHub account. Let me actually show you that.
So it was called as Codex Gram.
So I'm gonna visit that repo, and here you can tell we just got those changes just now.
Okay, so with this, I believe I'm gonna see you in the next lesson.
Alright, so in the previous lesson, we have generated the design for authentication screen. Now let's go ahead and see how we can take this and convert it into reality.
So there is a loop that I always use, which is basically we ask Cloud to take a screenshot from the simulator,
So let's say this is our authentication screen. We say take a screenshot and compare it to the end result. Until they're identical, go ahead and do it, right?
So this is like a loop.
First, we say go ahead and build the authentication screen.
And here is the workflow.
Take a screenshot from the simulator and compare it to the actual design.
And if it is identical, just stop.
If it is not, then keep going, right?
So this is like a loop, it is gonna run a couple of times, and once it is done, once it is identical, we'll just say, okay.
Um, I was saying once it is identical, just move on with the next feature or the next screen, whatever that is.
Okay, so with this in mind, let's go ahead and talk with Claude.
Sorry, with Codex in this case.
I'm not using Claude, but you got the point.
Here, I think I'll just open up a new chat.
And here I'll just try to explain it.
Alright, so I just pause the video and explain it. You can pause the video and read it.
Basically, this is exactly what I just explained, and I'm gonna go ahead and run this.
And let me just double check if I'm running the application.
I think I don't, so I'm just gonna say npx expo.
And I'll press R or you should press I if it is not running in the simulator.
Now it is right here as you can tell.
Now while this is trying to build it, we can create the we can create the clerk application.
So clerk is going to be the authentication service that we'll be using.
It is completely free to get started with, and you don't really need to pay anything, like you don't even need to put in your credit card information.
So just go ahead and create an account and then right here you can create a new application.
In my case, I have bunch of different apps, but let's let's start from scratch.
Let's give it a name. I'll just say codex gram. You can call this anything, and then just add the sign-in options that you'd like to have.
In my case, I'm going to disable the email, but I'll just have Google as well as Apple.
Now, one thing that I want to mention, if you include like if you include something like Google authentication, then you have to have Apple authentication as well,
right? So basically Apple tells you that if you include any other social integrations for the authentication, then you have to have Apple as well.
Otherwise, your application will be rejected.
And we'll go ahead and activate both of them in clerk dashboard and we'll say create the application.
Okay, so here they have a bunch of different SDKs literally for everything.
But in our case, we're gonna get the expo SDK.
Now we can copy the prompt and just let AI to set this up, and this is actually what I'll be doing.
But if you'd like to see the entire manual setup, then just press here, then you can go through it. What I'll be doing is just getting the environment variable.
So I'm gonna copy it and I'm gonna go right here,
create the.env file,
and I'll just paste this in.
So we have a publishable key.
Basically, with this key, we can
connect to this application that we just created.
You can think of it in that way.
And I think I'm gonna copy this prompt, but I'd like to implement authentication a little bit later in the video.
For now, let's just set up the UI design.
And I'll just be right back once this is completed.
Alright, so after around four minutes, we got the end result. I think this is looking pretty similar to the design that we attached.
Let me just actually find it.
Okay, so it is almost identical.
Like we have the three dots, which is right here, icon, logo,
literally everything.
What I'd like to get rid of is maybe this text.
I think it is just unnecessary.
So I can search for it and delete it myself.
A social app
trusted testers. So let's find it.
And I'll just delete this text.
I think it is unnecessary.
But other than this, I think this looks pretty clean, especially for the version 1.
Maybe later at some point we can update it.
Um, but yeah, for now I'll just leave it as it is.
Now let's go ahead and get this prompt.
I'm gonna copy it and then I'll paste it right here.
And I'll say
implement so I just said implement authentication with clerk, and here's the entire documentation.
And again, I'll just be right back once this is done because currently if you press nothing happens.
But now codex will implement it and it should work out.
Alright, so here you can tell it has built it, and now it's even using my computer and testing out by itself.
Like this is Codex, it has clicked to it, and now I think it's gonna go ahead and say continue or cancel.
Like it's literally testing this out.
Now, what I'll be doing is basically just stopping this process because I believe it is already implemented successfully.
I'll just go ahead and test this out. So I'm gonna press this button and let's say continue.
I already have an account that I signed in in the past.
Um, like what is going on? Let's just say cancel and
Wait, I think I'm just gonna close this first.
And okay, so I believe, like here you can tell, we got the Codex GRAM, and this is the development build.
This is something that I have briefly mentioned in the past, but I never told you how we can get this.
So I think you know, as you can tell, Codex has already got the development build, but let's say you don't really know how to do it.
I'll try to explain pretty quickly.
So, first off, there is something called expo dev client.
This is a package that you can take a look at it or a module.
You would copy this, okay, and paste it into your terminal.
npx expo install expo dev client.
Once you have this, you would go into your terminal and let's say you would just
open up a new terminal, okay, and then you would say npx expo run iOS or Android if you're building it for Android.
So in my case, it's gonna be iOS and looks like Codex has already run it.
If you take a look at it, right here I have an iOS folder, right?
If you run it with Android,
then you would have the Android folder as well.
And what this is, basically, this is the entire application, right?
But it is built under the iOS folder.
So this is a development build. Now we can see it is right here.
Okay, so it is much more than this, but we can keep it like this to explain it simply.
Okay, so from here and out, whenever I want to run my application, I'll just run it from here.
I'm not gonna go ahead and open up the XboGo application because as I said, that's that was for testing purposes for small applications.
Okay, I hope that this makes sense.
Now we'll go ahead and just say
continue with Google.
And before I say continue, if you press Ctrl D, you're gonna get the developer developer tools, and here you can toggle the tools button,
which is this one.
This is just for development purposes. You will not see this if you publish your app to the app store.
Okay, so here you can toggle the state, you can have the fast refresh, reload, go home, basically everything.
And now we'll just say continue with Google and we'll test out if the authentication will work.
So this takes some time, but
I don't know why. I'll try to ctrl D and reload.
Okay.
Now we'll try to sign up
because if you currently take a look at it under the users, we don't really have any account.
Oh, I think we have, and I believe that's because the Codex has tests this out in the background.
Um, but yeah, right here, now we just logged in.
We can sign out as well,
and we'll be right here. Okay, so that's the authentication. It is implemented in simple terms.
You can also test out with Apple, but since Google is working, like this is also working 100%, but I'm just not gonna test this out.
Um, with this, what I have done off camera is that I went into GPT, into the same chat history. This is where we left.
I said upscale the home screen, profile and chat screens, generate each of them as a separate image.
So we have the chat screen,
we have the home, and we have the profile screen.
So I'm going to copy every single one of these images
and go into VS Code.
Let's maximize the screen
under the design.
I'm going to paste oops, I'm going to paste this one.
Let's call this as home screen reference
and let's go into GPT.
Basically, I'll do the same thing for the other screens.
This is gonna be chat screen reference, and then finally, I believe the profile screen.
Okay.
Now the other thing that I have done is basically generating more screen. I said upscale the explore screen, which is this one.
Um it is this one.
Then I said the edit profile sheet,
comment sheet, and I said generate every single one of them as a separate image.
So here you can tell we have the comments.
So these are needed for GPT or codex to copy it.
So what you would like to do is copying them and pasting it right here.
And I'll say explore screen
reference.
Now I'm gonna get the other images as well, but here I think I'd like to go into codex and I'll say just like in the authentication screen,
I want you to build the home screen where we have that loop, right?
So I'll try to explain it.
Let me show you that pretty quickly.
Okay, so I'll just say put yourself into this loop once again and build the home screen.
For now, we don't have a database, we don't have any data.
So I'll just say create some test or some fake data, just like one of these, and build the UI.
So I just pause the video and get my prompt.
And here, if you wanted to reference an image, which is home screen, you can just say add and then add the file name.
So that's going to be home screenrev.png.
I'll go ahead and run this. Once this is done, I'll just be right back.
So currently it has built it and it is still within that loop, like it's literally trying to compare it to the end result and trying to fix the issues.
And currently I can see like there is one issue right here.
Um, it should fix that kind of like overflow, it should look like this.
Um so yeah, I'll just wait for this to be completed.
Once it is done, I'll just be right back.
But this looks identical, like literally the exact same end result.
all right so GPT is done with it, but still there are some issues that it didn't really fix, which is something that you shouldn't really get mad at because it is AI at the end of the day.
You should take the screenshots and follow up.
This is what I do, like I will literally take a screenshot and then paste it right here.
And instead of adding couple of updates or a couple of fixes in one prompt, what I do is asking for one fix at a time.
So here I just took the screenshot and I'll say fix this overflow.
Okay, so once this is done, and then I'll follow up, I'll say
um use the native tabs for these tabs, right?
Once again, native tabs are something that we have in Expo. You can double check.
This will give us the iOS liquid glass effect.
If you wanted to, you can copy the entire page as markdown.
This will get you know the entire page as a documentation,
and you can paste it right here.
Actually, this is what I'll be doing. I'll say
let's say something like convert tabs to native tabs, and here is the
entire documentation, and then you would paste this.
Now I'm gonna run this, but let's first wait for this to be completed, and I think it is already done.
Now,
you know, GPD is trying to use my simulator and test this out.
Okay, so here you can tell.
I think here we don't really have an overflow, but the image is not really.
Like, can you see the image has the black background, which is something that we can fix. This is some hard-coded test data, anyways.
Okay, so I'll go ahead and run this.
Now, in a couple of minutes, the tabs should be converted to native tabs.
All right so after five minutes, it was able to build the native tabs.
As you can tell, it is looking really, really clean compared to the previous version.
Now there was kind of like an issue.
Here you can tell it, the background was kind of like gray, but now it is transparent.
That's because I asked it.
So here I took the screenshot and I said native tabs looks as I want it, but remove that gray background.
So the rest of the application is visible, right?
Previously, here I had some gray background.
Here you can tell.
Um, but now we don't really have it.
As you can tell, it just fixed it under one minute.
So with this, I hope you are able to see my workflow.
Now, in the exact same way, I'll go ahead and build the profile screen, you know, explore screen, and even the messages screen.
Here I think I added a couple of more images off camera.
So we had the profile, home.
I have added the edit profile reference, right? The screen.
I have added the comment screen as well, and I believe the chat screen.
Okay, so these are some of the screens that I have added off camera.
Other than this, I haven't updated anything in the code base.
Now I'll go ahead and just say, now do the exact same thing for the profile screen.
Once it is done, I'll just be right back.
So just for the record, here is my prompt. I said now build the profile screen, use that loop, and here is the reference image that I just attached.
All right, so in six minutes it was able to build and test that out.
This is the profile screen.
Now I just said build the edit profile, and here is the reference image.
So I'm gonna run this. Once it is done, I'll be right back.
Now you might be asking why don't we implement anything now?
Well, that's because I think it's always better to have the entire the entire UI design, and then it's gonna be really easy to replace everything with the actual data.
For now, like this is my workflow, I'm trying to get the UI design as much as possible.
And once I wanted to implement the actual back end, all I need to do is just replacing this data with the actual data.
Okay, so we're going to set up convex in the incoming sections, but for now let's just go ahead and build most of the UI design.
all right so after some time, here we go, it's also been built, but I think having the sign out here doesn't make any sense.
That's what we have in our UI design, so I cannot really blame codex, but I'll just say delete the sign up button from here.
Maybe we should have it under the settings.
So basically, when we press this button, there should be some kind of settings screen, and I'm gonna get into that and I'm gonna get into that a little bit later in the video.
So for now I'll just say delete the sign up button from edit profile screen.
And also what I'll be doing is taking a screenshot from right here, I'll just say replace the three dots
with a settings icon.
Later we will build that page.
Okay, now it says I have removed the sign up button.
Yes, it is not here, and now we should update this part as well.
Now while it is trying to update it, let's go ahead and say build the explore page.
We already have something here, but it is not the design.
Like this is something codex generated for fun in the past.
Um basically I would like to get this one.
So I'm just going to reference this.
Let's say build the explore screen.
And here you can tell that this has been updated to settings and we'll implement it a little bit later in the video.
Alright, so after some time, the explore screen is ready. Here you can tell.
We're gonna replace them with the actual data a bit later in the video.
And after explore screen, I just added the chat screen reference and then I said build the screen as well. So we have a fake account or a chat.
If we press that, we have the actual details where we can send the message.
This is something again we're gonna get into the details and the implementation a little bit later in the video.
But with this, I think we can leave this section right here where we build the entire UI design from the authentication screen to the profile
and basically everything that we we would need for the version one.
Now just before I commit my changes and in this section, there is one thing that I want to talk about.
Let's go into the workflow that we had so far.
So we have built our plan, we have generated the UI design, we break it into features like authentication and UI design.
So far, we have only built these, right? So you're gonna build one feature at a time.
That's what we have done. We built the authentication screen, and then we have built the rest of the page.
sorry, rest of the design.
We did like a self-check, we manually tested most of the things if they're working or not, and it turns out everything has passed.
But now we need to run an AI code review.
This is at least what I do as a part of my workflow, because it looks like everything is working, but in my code base, there could be a lot of different security issues that I cannot really see.
So for that reason, I want to have an AI that can, you know, like scan my entire code base and see if I have any issues
or if I'm not following any conventions, so on and so forth.
Now, for this, there are a bunch of different tools, and one of the free tools that you can get started with is gonna be CodeRabbit.
It's completely free to sign up and you'll get like two weeks of free trial.
And I already have an account, so just go ahead and log in with your GitHub account, then you would like to visit this section where you have repositories.
So once you're here, you can go ahead and add your repositories manually or you can sync all of them at once.
This is what I have done. I basically have all my repositories in the CodeRabbit dashboard.
Now, anytime you would like to use CodeRabbit for the AI code review, you need to send a pull request.
Or you can do like on the main branch as well, but I'd like to create separate branches.
And if you don't know what that means, let me try to explain pretty quickly.
So just imagine this is the timeline, right?
And you're building features every single next day, okay?
So today you started with the authentication, next you added the UI design, next you add the you know messaging feature, and now you'd like to add the video
calling feature, right?
But you don't really know if it is going to break or if your teammates will accept it or not.
So you say instead of me updating the code directly, right?
Instead of me updating the actual branch, let me go ahead and create a testing branch, right?
And then here I'll add some changes, like I'm gonna add the audio calling and then video calling, and then you're gonna commit them.
Now let's say you like the actual end result, then you can send a pull request and you can say if you're working with your teammates, you can say something like
here I have built the video calling feature, can you please accept my request?
And if they accept it, now your changes will be added into the actual actual branch, which is what we call either main
or master.
Now let's say your team actually like this feature, they can accept it, and then later at some point, you can delete this branch and like you don't really need it anymore.
And your changes are right here.
Or let's say they didn't really like it, they say this is breaking our code, or I don't know, we don't want to have video calling feature, something like that.
They're gonna reject your pull request, and then you can basically go ahead and you know delete this branch as if nothing has happened.
Alright, so that's the general idea behind it. If you're a beginner, like if you have never seen this before, it might feel a little bit abstract, but like that's the general idea behind it.
You create separate branches, right?
And you can add more features, then at some point just take it back or push it to the main branch.
So just imagine like you are 10 different people in a project, everyone can create their own branches and work on different features,
right?
Eventually everything will be merged to the main branch.
Okay, so I hope that's not really confusing.
Now let's go into VS Code and see how we can create a separate branch and commit our changes.
So first off, I'll maximize the screen and I'm gonna press Command Shift P.
Or if you're on Windows, that's gonna be control Shift P.
Then here you can say toggle status bar visibility.
From right here, I think, excuse me, I'm gonna select create new branch.
By default, I'm on master as you can tell.
In your case, this might be main, which is fine, it is the same thing.
Um, just go ahead and say create a new branch, and then let's give it a name.
I'll just say oath and let's say UI design.
all right so currently we created this branch, right? Now let's try to commit our changes.
So you'll go right here,
scroll to the top,
stage everything by pressing this button.
Let's get a commit message.
So that's the message AI generated for me.
I'll go ahead and commit this.
Okay, and then we'll say publish this branch.
Now, if you go and take a look at your source code,
like just go ahead and reload.
So this is still taking some time, but now we should have this new branch, right? It is right here for four seconds ago.
I'll go ahead and say create a pull request.
Now, if you scroll to the bottom, you'll be able to see how many lines of changes you have.
You know, like this is the amount of new additions, and these are the deletions, and then you can scroll and see every single change that you have.
Now instead of so instead of reviewing them manually, we'll just let AI to scan every single line and tell us what are the things that we can fix.
I'll just say create the pull request.
If you have set it up this correctly, right, you should be able to get a code review in a couple of minutes.
Alright, so initially this is what you're gonna see, and it's gonna take a couple of minutes.
Once it is done, you'll get the feedback from code rabbit.
And once it is done, I'll just be right back.
all right so after 10 minutes, the code review is ready.
Now we can scroll to the bottom and see every single suggestions that we have.
So since we didn't really implement it anything important in our code other than UI design, we don't really have that big of issues.
But here you can tell we have a minor suggestion, and then another one.
Yeah, I think currently we only have two.
And if you want to fix them, you can obviously copy the prompt and paste it to AI, and you can also like see the problem, why this is a suggestion,
like what CodeRabbit thinks, and how can you fix them, right?
Now just imagine you have 10 different suggestions.
You don't really want to copy every single one of them one by one.
So you can scroll to the top and you can just get the prompt for all review comments for AI agents, right?
So I'm gonna copy this and let's go back into VS Code.
And like right here, I'll paste my prompt.
So this will go ahead and fix those issues.
And once it is done, we can add another commit and then
you know send it as a pull request once again.
So currently we are right here.
So we created our commit.
We sent the pull request, right?
And before we say merge the pull request,
um we would like to run these fixes.
So here you can tell within the next one minute everything has been fixed.
Let's go ahead and stage these, and we are gonna create a new commit.
You don't really need to create a new pull request.
So I'll just say sync the changes.
If you scroll to the top, now you're gonna have that we'll have the two commits.
Initially we had one, it just reloaded by itself.
Now we can scroll to the bottom and just say, you know, merge this pull request.
Now code rabbit will try to give you another review because you just had a new commit, but we don't really need to wait for it because
these were the suggestions that came from CodeRabbit.
Okay, so I'll go ahead and confirm the merge. Basically, we say yes, you are accepting this, now your changes will be on the master branch.
Okay, I'll try to visualize it and show you every single step creating the branch, adding the commit, sending the pull request, and merging it.
Now with this, everything is done.
You can go back to your master branch,
just select this one, and then press this button, right?
We're just going to sync this up.
Oh wait, we have a.mv change, how come?
it was to change here?
I think we have the secret key. This is something that Codex added behind the scenes.
It's not really that important for now. Just go ahead and press this button.
You probably don't have this.
I don't know.
just go ahead, press this button, and this is going to sync it up.
Basically, it'll get the latest changes and update your code base with it.
Alright, so this is where we left.
Now that we have most of the UI design ready, it is time to get started with the actual functionalities.
So we should be able to create posts, you know, like them, comment, send messages, so on and so forth.
For this, we're gonna need a backend and basically a database.
And for this, we can use convex, which is completely free to get started with.
You don't really need to pay anything. Here you can tell they have a really, really generous free plan.
And I already have an account.
If you don't, go ahead and sign up, then log in with your GitHub account, and then you will go into VS Code.
Now we can ask AI to implement it for you, but what I'll be doing is just setting it up, setting it up by myself so that you can see the process
instead of just you know blindly vibe coding.
Okay, so here I don't know what is happening with the terminal UI.
Okay, now it's fixed. Now from here and out, you almost always want to have two different terminals.
In one of them, you are gonna run the expo application with npx expo, and with the other terminal, you would like to run
convex, okay, which is our backend.
So here go ahead and just type npm install convex.
First, this is going to install the package, and then we are gonna run npxconvexdev.
So just wait for it.
This will install the package.
Okay, so this is taking a little bit longer than it should.
While this is installing, I have done something in the background, which is basically generating a different logo, and because I didn't really like this one.
So I went into GPT.
Here I'll show you the steps.
So this is where we left, right?
I just said generate a grid of nine of icons for this app that I can choose from.
And I didn't really like any of them. Let's say if I like this one, I would say upscale the option five.
But clearly I don't like any of them, so I just said give me a completely different style and vibe.
Again, a grid of nine. From here, I like the option six.
I just said upscale this and make it in the blue theme.
This is what it gave me.
Even though it's not the same thing, I still really like this one.
And then I just said, you know, remove the background.
So this is one of the other processes that I just wanted to show you.
If you want to get a different variation of something, just ask for a grid of nine instead of asking nine different times.
So from here, let's say you like this one, you'll just say upscale this for me.
So with that in mind, you'd like to copy this image or the logo, right?
I'll just go into my assets
and I'll just paste it. Actually, under the images, I'll say control V and I'll be using it in a second.
So for now we have the convex installed. Let's clear this up.
You'll say MPX convex
dev.
So initially,
it might ask you to log in if you're running it for the first time.
But I have already logged in, right?
And this is going to be the next question that you're going to get if you are logged in.
we would like to create a new project. So I'll just select this one, let's give it a name.
I'll just say codex gram. It is taking from the folder name, so I'll just press tab and I'll press enter.
If you wanted to, you can type something else to update this name.
but I'll leave it as it is, and we would like to deploy it on the cloud.
Just go ahead and press enter.
And we would like to set up convex AI files such as agents.md and some skills.
Basically, this will teach AI how to work with convex in the best way possible.
Okay, so this will create a couple of different files, and actually most of them will be under a folder called convex.
Okay, so our entire backend code will be under right here, right?
And like, we'll have schema, we'll have different mutations, queries.
and if you don't know what that means, is basically you have queries to fetch data, like getting the posts, and to create something,
you would have mutations like creating a comment, creating a post, or deleting a post, deleting a comment,
updating.
things like that. So for this, AI will create some mutations for us.
Okay, I'm only explaining this if you're just a vibe coder and watching it up up until now.
Um, I think these
would be helpful just to know.
Okay, so with this, from here on out, always have this terminal open and you can rename it just by pressing enter or press right,
say rename. I'll just say convex, and you can rename this one as well. You can say expo, mobile, whatever you'd like to call.
Okay, now with this, what I'll be doing is going into
a new chat. First off, I'll just say use the logo that I have right here.
So I'm gonna call this as logo.png.
And I'll just say use this logo.png as my brand logo in this app.
We can say something like replace the current one with this one.
Alright, so within 50 seconds, as you can tell, icons have been updated within this application.
Now here I'm going to maximize the screen, and here is my prompt.
You can pause the video and read it, but I basically say now that we have authentication and most of the UI design ready,
just go ahead and read my plan.md so that you know what kind of features we want to build. And then I say just go ahead and start implementing the post creation, likes, comments, and follows.
And then I say let me know if I need to set up anything from the clerk or convex dashboard.
Okay, so this is what you would like to do at the end. Just say, you know, like let me know if there is anything that I need to do manually from any of these dashboards.
And I'll run this.
Let's see what we're gonna get back.
So while it is building, I just got asked a question. It says, is the convex integration enabled in your clerk dashboard?
If not, it says go under the integrations and find the convex.
So here I'll go ahead and
find my project, go under the configure, and then you can just search for integration.
So go ahead and press this, it is under the developers, and then right here go ahead and turn this on for convex.
And then go back into VS Code here. Let's say it is enabled.
all right so after 20 minutes, looks like everything has been implemented just like as we requested, and it says you don't really need to add anything,
you know, like nothing you need to do from the dashboard.
And here you can tell if you remember, we said that user has to first set up a username to be able to use this application.
So here it says, first off, go ahead and add a username.
Here I'll just try to put my name
and let's put the last name. I'll say continue.
It's going to create the profile. For now, we don't really have any data, that's why everything is empty, right?
The UI is
UI is filled in with empty state.
Okay, let's go ahead and create a post.
Here I'll just try to select something from my gallery.
let's go ahead and select this one.
And here I'll say something like this weekend
trip.
And let's put three dots. I was gonna say,
and I'll say publish.
So here we had the indicator and looks like this has been uploaded.
We can double check by going into our convex dashboard.
I'll try to log in.
Now, once you log in, go ahead and select the current application and make sure you're under the development.
From here, I'll just say files.
Here you can tell we have a file that has just been uploaded.
Now, usually you can hover over this and see the end result.
I'll try to install it. Let's see.
Okay, here you can tell that's the image that's been uploaded to Convex.
Now, with this, I think we can also take a look at the data.
Here you can tell we have a bunch of different tables like uploads, profiles.
This is the only user profile that we have.
Now you might be wondering how do we get this user right here, right?
And I think that's because we have configured the convex integration in clerk.
So it is like set it up already automatically.
Now let's try to test out some more features. I'm gonna like
here we go, I'll try to add a comment.
Maybe we have a UI glitch here that we can fix.
I'll just say test comment, and actually at the same time, I'll just take a screenshot,
go into codex,
and I'll say fix the comment section.
It should be
a bit more spaced out from the bottom.
And then I'll try to post.
Here we go, it is right here.
Now UI is not really that great.
Um, I'll try to kind of like format it, and what I'll be doing is actually taking a screenshot, and I'll go under GPT
right here.
I'll paste this in and then I'll say something like
this is the current UI that I have for the pose detail screen. I want you to give me three different variations of this UI.
try to keep it simple and make sure it is matching with the blue color palette that we have already.
Um, yeah, just give me three different variations.
So this will give me that three variations, and from those three images, I'll try to choose one and we'll ask
Codex to implement it for us.
Okay, so in the background, it's gonna go ahead and implement it.
And let's see, okay, that has been fixed, as you can tell in 30 seconds it is done.
Now I can tell something like delete.
If you say cancel, nothing happens, obviously, but if you delete, comment should be gone. Here you can tell everything updates automatically.
Now, one thing to mention about convex is that everything is real time out of the box.
So here just imagine you write a comment and you have another simulator running right here.
If they are looking right here on this post, as soon as you post, like they will see this comment on that other simulator in real time.
They don't need to reload the application.
Now, one of the other things that I'll ask Codex is to add some seeded data.
If you don't know what that means, is basically some hard-coded test data so that we can see how the rest of the application look like. So currently under the explorer, we only have one post.
But how would it look like if we had like 20 different posts, right? So I'm gonna say add some seeded data.
That would be helpful for me to see
the rest of the app with a lot of data.
So probably this part is not really that important, but I'll just add it anyways, and let's run it.
Alright, so it took around 10 minutes, and here we go. We have now 24 fictional profiles, this amount of photos, you know, likes and comments.
If you visit the explorer, you'll be able to see all these posts, different accounts, and if you press them, you're gonna get the details with likes,
comments, and you can also like or comment.
So we have the home screen, this is how that look like.
We have the profile, we're following
this amount of accounts, and sorry, all the accounts are actually following us because this is the amount of profiles that have been created, and we are following 12 of them.
So I think that's a really nice start, and we can go ahead and try to visit some accounts and actually try to follow them.
Notice how you know UI is not the best, but we can always follow up and put codex into a loop,
which is something that I'll get into in the incoming sections. But for now, I think we can follow and unfollow.
Um, here I'll just say unfollow. I don't know why, but it takes some time.
Because I think it is running on the background.
This is something that we can make a little bit faster as well.
Okay, so with this, I think with this, I think I'll just take a quick break and then I'll just be right back.
Alright, so now let's go ahead and implement the chat messaging.
Currently, everything that you see on the screen is completely fake.
Like this data is hard-coded.
So here I'll just say implement the chat messaging and let's go ahead and reference this screen.
So I'm gonna say chat
screenref.png.
Now when it comes to the this screen, it doesn't really look that good.
So for this, I'll also provide some references.
Now to generate a different reference for the screen, I took a screenshot, I went into GPT, and then I just said give me a grid of three for this UI.
And then I just said make sure that it is matching with the rest of the design system.
So it gives me three different variations.
This is the one that I actually like.
So here I just said you know, upscale the variation third,
and here we go, we have it.
Now I'm gonna copy this image.
Let's go ahead and paste it right here under the design.
I'm gonna say something like messages tab reference
and let's try to shrink the left hand side.
And here I'll also add the
messages tab reference.
And then let's say
put yourself into a loop
so you can pause the video and read my prompt.
But this is something that we have done multiple times at this point.
I'll go ahead and run this and I'll just be right back once this is done.
All right so in my case, this took around 17 minutes.
It has actually built it pretty quickly, but then it takes some time to test out every single thing just to make sure that this feature is working as expected.
Now, what you see here is still fake data, and I asked because when I checked the database, let me actually display it, I didn't really see any messages, and I'm like,
what is going on, right?
So I just went into VS Code, I said when we sent a message, does it get saved to the database or all of this data are still hard-coded? And it says both of them exists.
Basically, since they are like demo accounts, what you see here is fake data.
But it says if you want to actually test this out, go ahead and sign up with a different account, and everything should be working out as expected,
which is something that I'm gonna test out a little bit later in the video.
But for now, there is one thing that I have done off camera that I'd like to show you pretty quickly.
Um, so first off, let me show you the post detail screen.
This is currently what we have, and I didn't really like this that much, so I went into GPT.
Let me show you that exact part.
So here I took the screenshot and I said this is the current UI, which I don't really like. So I said give me three different variations, and it almost gave me the exact same thing.
So what I have done is attaching the design system, and I said give me those three different variations depending on our UI,
sorry, our design system, and from here I try to upscale the second variation, which is this one,
like this is the one that I liked most.
So here at the very end, you'll see that I said upscale this
second version.
So I'm gonna copy it, go into VS Code under the design,
paste this in, and let's call this as post detail
ref.
And then I'll put my simulator right on the side, and I'll just say, you know, go ahead update the pulse screen, just like this one.
And one thing I realize is that I don't really want to copy everything exactly as is, because I think this header part is looking better than what
what we have right here.
So what I'd like to do is actually copy this
bottom part and paste it right here. I'll say only update this part, right?
So here I'll take this screenshot.
So
here's my prompt. You can pause the video and read it.
I try to basically explain what I just said, and I'm gonna run this. Once this is done, I'll just be right back.
all right so within the next 10 minutes, it was ready. Here you can tell the actions, the comments, almost everything is identical to what we have right here.
I'm pretty happy with how that ended up, so I'll just not follow up with any other improvements when it comes to this screen.
If you wanted to, you can of course do it anytime you want.
Now we can add more features, and I think I'm gonna get into that in the next sections, but for now, what I'd like to do is running this application
in my actual phone, right?
So instead of running it only in simulator, I'll go ahead and install this development build in my actual phone.
Now there are two different ways of doing it.
The first one is connecting your phone with a USB cable to your Mac, right?
And then you would run this command.
Now I'll just open up my terminal and let's go under the expo terminal.
Let's clear this up.
Let me maximize the screen. You would say npx expo run iOS, just like previously. This is what we have done, but at the end you would say dash dash device.
Now, if you have your phone connected with USB cable, you're gonna see it right here in one of the options.
So mine is not connected, but since I have done it in the past, it shows me this.
And the other way of running this is that you would use expo EAS.
If you don't know what that is, let's go ahead and double check.
So I'll just say expo EAS.
So Expo Application Services.
This is a service that allows you to run a development build in your phone.
This allows you to, you know, publish your app to the App Store, Play Store, literally every single service that you can ever imagine.
Now, you don't really need to learn everything from absolute scratch, just go ahead and explain it to Codex or Cloud for this current use case, and it's gonna give you all the steps.
Now, of course, I would say if you're interested or if you are serious about mobile development, just pause the video and go ahead, read this entire page,
take a look at the documentation, and then come back.
But if you're just here to test things out, then you can just go into Codex or Cloud and ask for the
you know the instructions.
And by the way, what you see here on the screen is for Apple Developer Program.
Basically, this is something that you need to apply if you want to publish your app to the App Store.
Apple wants you to pay $99 per year for this program, and you know, if you live outside of US, with you know in a country with lower local purchase,
then this price will be discounted for you.
So I think you'll get something in between 20 to 25 dollars, or really, you know, it's gonna depend on the country that you live in.
So I'm from Turkey. When I applied, I paid something between between this amount, but you know, if you're in a different country, it could be even lower than this
or a little bit higher than this.
So I don't know, maybe it could be $50,
or maybe even like $10.
I don't know.
but this is something to keep in mind.
If you actually want to publish your app, this is something that you have to apply.
And unfortunately, this is not something that I came up with.
This is something that Apple wants you to apply and pay for.
Okay, just keep this in mind. This is something that I wanted to mention.
You can always double check just before publishing your app.
Okay, so with that said, now I'll go into codex.
I'm gonna kill this terminal by the way. Here I'll say I'd like to get a development build and install it in my phone.
And I'll say I want to use EAS, right? Expo application services.
So I'll say what I need to do, give me everything step by step.
Basically, you need to run a command in your terminal.
I already know what that is, but here I'll just act as if I don't know it, and I'll try to show you what what you should do in these type of scenarios.
Okay, so here you can tell this is my prompt. You can read it if you're interested.
I'm gonna run this and we're gonna get a prompt or a command that we can run in our terminal.
And this will create also a file called Eas.json.
Currently we don't really have it, but we're gonna get that, and it is like the configuration file that EAS needs.
Okay,
so I'll just wait for this to be completed. And once again, remember there are two different ways that we talked about.
The first one is running this command with the device flag and plug in your iOS to your Mac, right?
And I mean iPhone, not iOS, but you got the point.
That was the first way.
The second way is using EAS.
This is what I'll be using, and in this way you'll be able to see the entire process.
Alright, so here we go, we have all the instructions.
This is the things that you would run for the very first time.
But since I have already built different mobile applications, I already have the device connections and you know I already logged into
EAS, initialized it, etc.
So what I would do is scrolling to the bottom, and then I just said give me the command to get a development build on the cloud.
So I'm gonna run this, but once again, if you are doing it for the very first time, you need to log in in it and create that connection to your device.
So everything that it gives you here will be correct.
And you can always follow up and say, you know, like I am a complete beginner, I have never done this before, so tell me all the steps that I need to do.
Okay.
So this is just something to keep in mind.
In my case, I want to get it for iOS, but if you want to get it for Android, leave everything as it is, but update this part as Android.
Now I'll go into my terminal, I'll paste this in.
And it'll ask me a couple of different questions.
Um, looks like this has failed.
It says invalid version.
I'll just copy this and paste it right here.
So after I just paste this to Codex, it has given me the solution. Basically, it has fixed the cache and then it says rerun this.
This is exactly what I have done.
I basically rerun this command. Now I'm gonna get a bunch of different questions.
You're gonna get the same questions, just go ahead and press enter a couple of different times until it starts to build.
Alright, so as you can tell, now it is uploading to the EAS.
You can always go into your actual dashboard. Let's actually see it.
I'll visit expo.dev.
And here I have already logged into my account.
Here you can tell that these are the previous projects that I created.
Now we just got the latest one just now.
And if you press this, you can see that we have a development build that is getting created, right?
We are getting this build.
So once it is done, we should be able to install it to our actual phone.
So in my case, it has failed, which is completely normal.
And here is the fix.
You would go right here and let's find the step that it has failed for the first time. Like it was going successfully, right here, it has failed.
So I'll just press this button, which will get me the logs, which is basically the details.
If you don't know what that means, I'm gonna paste this in and I'll say, like you don't need to even say anything, but I'll just say my
dev build failed, and
here are the logs.
Hopefully, this should give us a fix.
Once it is fixed, we are going to rerun this.
Alright, so here we can tell that this has been fixed. It says go ahead and rerun this command, but I also realized that we have a lot of different changes.
Now, as far as I know, that we have to commit these to get a EAS build, but I'll just double check, I'll say
I have uncommitted changes.
Do I have to commit them beforehand?
Like I believe we have to commit them because EAS would get a snapshot.
Um, but looks like it says no.
Okay, so that's fine.
Maybe I'm just wrong.
I'm gonna I'm gonna go ahead and clear this up.
I'll paste this and again I'll press enter a couple of different times.
We're gonna get a new development build.
Like you should be able to see the new build right here.
So here you can tell we have the build.
Again, it is getting built. Let's just wait if it is going to fail or not.
I'll just be right back.
Alright, so after a couple of minutes, the process will be ended successfully, and you're gonna get a QR code.
Now I just scanned this in my phone, and this is what I got.
Basically, it has installed the application, and if you press that you're gonna get this UI.
So here you can tell we have the logo, the name, and it is trying to find the development server.
Now let's say you are confused and you don't know how to run the app because it doesn't run it by default.
You can just say, now in my terminal I have a QR code. How do I run this? Like what do I do?
So here are the steps that you will do.
First off, scan the QR code, it's going to install the build, and then under the settings, privacy and security, you need to have the developer mode if this is prompted.
If not, it's okay.
Then you need to just go ahead and run this on your Mac.
So basically scroll right here and run this command.
Now, even after running this command, if you see the exact same end result, then go ahead run the same command with the tunnel
flag.
So this is what I'll be doing.
I will run this and then at the same time I'm just checking my phone.
So I'll open up the application.
So currently you don't see, but I have my phone, it is right here. I'll try to actually visit this app.
Okay, so here again I have the same UI, but this time I will fill this in with a value.
So here you can tell it says it should start with HTTP, and you can find it right here.
So after the URL, just copy this part,
okay, up until the direct included.
So copy this and then go into your phone, then just paste it.
So I just pasted it, as you can tell, it is trying to build.
And let me open up my camera and actually show you that.
Okay, so here you can tell I am in the loading screen. Currently it is loading, and our application is live.
So here you can tell that's the authentication screen.
Like literally everything is right here.
I'll go ahead and try to log in with my Google account.
Here it says continue.
And then let me just log in with one of my accounts.
Okay, so here it says you need to put in a username.
Let me just put something like my phone.
I'll continue and
let's see what we're gonna get.
Okay, so our feed is empty because we don't really follow anyone.
But if we go under the explore screen, here you can tell we have literally everything.
So it is working just like as our simulator.
I'll try to go ahead and send messages.
But first let me try to add these accounts.
Alright, so here in my phone, I went under the explore, and right here I searched for this account, which is this one,
right?
So I'll try to follow him now.
And as soon as I press the follow, notice how this updates automatically, right?
So everything is working in real time.
I'll try to unfollow.
Um
I can't press.
I just pressed and notice how it's been updated.
I'll try to press again and just watch here.
It is updating in real time.
Now let's go ahead and send a message.
I'll go under the messages
in my phone. Let me just send a message to this user.
I'll say hey.
And as you can tell, in real time, we just got the message.
And here I'll say, like I'm texting again, I'll say, How are you doing?
Like as soon as I send,
it is right here. And let's send a message from here as well.
If I send it
in real time, so everything is working as expected.
Now, other than the messages, everything else is also working in real time.
So here, notice how we have only one like from my phone. I'll try to like it, and as soon as I like, notice how it is getting updated.
I'll try to add a comment.
So I'll just say, hey, as soon as I post it, it is right here.
So that's the beauty of Convex.
Alright, so with this, I think I'm gonna leave this lesson right here.
Now we can improve the UI a lot, and this is something that we can do in the incoming lessons, and also we can add things like privacy policy,
terms of services, a setting screen, so on and so forth.
So these are the things that I'll leave for the incoming sections, but for now let's just go ahead and commit our changes and basically end this lesson.
Now I think the beauty of this lesson or the key takeaway here is that you have learned how to get a development build and how to install it in your actual phone.
Okay, so we'll go ahead and
even like kill everything.
I'm gonna stage every single change and I'll get a commit message.
Now, if I was building it as my real project, what I would do is again running a code review, just like here in our workflow,
by creating a pull request.
But in this case, I'll just go ahead and commit this on the master branch so that we don't really waste any time.
So I'll sync this up, and here you can tell I have a pop up from the code rapid extension, which is something that you can get for free in VS Code.
Just go ahead and search for it, which will be code rapid.
So you can install this and it'll work out of the box.
Okay, so with this, hopefully okay, so with this, hopefully I'll see you in the next lesson.
Alright, so this is where we left.
Off camera, I have done some small things and I'd like to walk you through it like what I have implemented in the background.
So first off, in the explore screen, we didn't really have this UI previously.
It was just the images only.
Now what I said is basically I give the reference image and I said, put yourself into that loop until you know we have the exact same end result.
And we have used this loop multiple times, so I'm not going to explain what is going on here.
So it took around 13 minutes and it was ready.
This was one-shotted without any issues.
Now there are a couple of different things that we need to update, such as the icon, it should match with the you know the updated icon that we have right here.
And also when you press this, the icon changes.
This is something that we can fix a little bit later in the video.
Okay, so other than this, I said do the exact same thing for the home screen, but do not change the icon. Here you can read my prompt.
And I also said implement the stories feature. And actually it is working, like I have already tested this out and I have posted something on my story.
And let's actually test it once again. Here you can press the button and select something from your library, or you can choose it from sorry, we can take it from your camera.
So here I'll go ahead and maybe post this one.
Now, one thing I'd like to say before I publish this in the very first version, we were able to write a caption in this story.
So I said go ahead and delete that feature from the stories, and I also said, you know, allow us to
take the photo from camera, not only from library.
And then I think I said in the post creation, keep the caption, but also add the camera option.
Okay, so I'll go ahead and publish this. This will take some time, but here we go.
If you press here, now we have two different stories, just like in Instagram.
You can go back, forward, and if you press again, if there were there are more stories, it's gonna go to the next one. Okay, so that was the very first thing that I have done.
And I think I run one more thing, which is the profile screen.
So again, I just said you know, put yourself into that loop and build the profile screen.
Now, here notice I didn't say put yourself into that loop, and and the reason for that is like every single time I don't want to explain this entire thing.
Let me show you.
So every single time I don't really want to say put yourself into a loop where you take a screenshot from simulator and compare it to the reference image and keep building until it's identical.
So like you need to create some kind of reusable component or a skill in this case, and I'll show you how I have generated it.
So you don't really need to type this every single time.
Okay, now for this, I'll just go into
my like how do we call it the file explorer, and under the cloud we have skills, right?
Under the agents we also have skills.
Now the difference between them, this one is only for cloud, but this is for literally any other thing, like codex cursor, you name it for everything.
But this is for only cloud.
Now I have edited in both of them just in case if you're using cloud or codex.
Uh, but yeah, basically, under the dot agents, we have skills.
If you scroll to the bottom, I created this file,
sorry, folder, and then the file called skill.md
and let me show you the file content.
So this is something that I have generated with Codex.
Basically, I said every single time I don't really want to type this, right? So I said create me a skill and put it under the agents folder as well as the cloud folder.
So this is literally what I have said.
Like I went here and then I said, I don't want to type this every single time. Can you please create me a skill?
And this is exactly what is happening in the background.
So you're gonna take this entire file and put it in your code base if you really wanted to, or I would say just take this as a challenge and go ahead and ask for codex
to generate the same thing for you.
Okay.
Um
so once you have this, you can create a new chat and just say something like, you know, make your profile screen looks like this image,
and just send the prompt.
You don't need to say, you know, put yourself into that loop. Because since this is a skill, it'll be already attached to the you know at the beginning of the conversation.
Let me try to kind of like visualize it.
So let's say this is your first chat, you say, go ahead and build me a profile screen, and then it says, Okay, I'll build it, and then you say something else, and uh, and then it'll do something else,
right? Now, here at the beginning of the chat, the session, that skill will be loaded automatically.
So that's the beauty of creating a skill.
And here I just left a comment, kind of like, how can we make this loop reusable?
Well, you would create a skill explaining everything.
And the beauty of this is that you don't really need to type everything by hand, you will just explain it to Codex or Cloud or whatever, and then you'll just say
create me this skill.
Okay, so I hope that helps.
Now, with this, I have the profile screen. It is also also looking pretty similar to the end result.
Now, here I said go ahead and delete the search icon as you can tell, and I also said replace this with the settings icon,
and we are gonna build a setting screen right here.
Now, here we can edit our profile, share the profile,
and sign out.
Now I think
I'll just say delete the edit profile button from here, also the share profile, we don't really need them, but what we need is delete
account and sign out buttons.
Now you might be asking why do we need the delete account button?
Well, it is mandatory, and if you don't have it, Apple will reject your application because you have authentication, you're storing user data.
When this user wants to delete their account, you need to give them that access, that permission.
So here I'll go ahead and type my prompt, I'll explain everything, and then I'll just be right back.
Now, actually, instead of going into codex and putting a prompt blindly, what I have done is something even better.
So I went into this chat that we already had with a GPT that is about design.
So I said I want you to give me a grid of three for setting screen.
You can read my prompt, but basically, I say give me things like we have privacy policy link, terms of services, delete
account, sign out, and some of the other things that you would need in a social media application.
Okay, so if you're wondering why do we need privacy policy and terms of services, well, once again, this is something that you must have.
If you don't link them, then your application will be rejected.
Also, when you publish your app to the App Store, Apple will ask you to provide these links.
So basically, you need to you need to build a privacy policy, terms of service, and deploy them on a live URL.
I'll try to show you how to generate them and publish them on the internet so that you can actually use those links.
Okay, so between these three options, I like the very first one. So I just said upscale the variation one.
This is what I got. I'll go ahead and copy
and paste it under the design.
You already know what I'm going to do next.
So I'll just say go ahead and build the settings screen.
Let's actually say settings screen reference just to be consistent with the rest of the names.
Here I'll just say settings screen ref
and let's say
build me this
Yeah, I think for now I'll just say build me this exact UI.
I'm gonna set my prompt and I'll just be right back once this is done.
So after around four minutes, this is what I got.
And here I just said go ahead and delete this header part, we don't really need it.
Now this should be done in a couple of seconds.
And I think overall I'm happy with the end result.
Like you can always
improve the UI, but that's not the goal of this tutorial, as you already know.
And one of the other things that it kind of failed, like we don't have native tabs anymore.
So I think for this we need to just simply tell
also bring back the native tabs.
Let's say remember, we always
want to use native tabs.
Now while this is building, I just want to mention that currently we're using AI in the very bad way.
Like this is not this is not optimal, it shouldn't really go from native tabs to the JavaScript tabs.
For this, I should have already set up a file called cloud.md or agents.md.
So here you can tell we already have these files.
Now let's talk about these files pretty quickly.
In simple terms, they are just a readme file for AI agents.
So here we have readme.md.
This is for humans, right? This is for developers.
But these are readme files for AI agents.
There's a difference between them, which is something that I'll get into in a second. But first, let's just read what they are in the first place.
So both are plain markdown instruction files that get auto-loaded into the AI's context at the start of a session.
They are let me just clear this.
They are where you put project conventions, architecture nodes, something like always do this, never do that, these type of rules.
So in our case, we could have just said always use native tabs, right?
Never use anything else for the tabs.
This is where you would put the instruction.
Now the difference between them is that cloud.md is for cloud and agents.md for literally anything else.
Okay, but I think cloud would still support this.
All you need to do is adding all your
instructions right here under the agents.md, and under the cloud.md, just go ahead and import it.
Okay, so that's all you need to do.
And this is a convention by the way. Here I have explained it as well.
Put your actual instructions in agents.md and make cloud to import that file.
Okay, now I think we we know the difference.
And here when I ask AI to implement the native tabs, I said we always want to use native tabs, right?
And here it says I have updated it under the agents.md.
So if I go under the agents.md and search for native tabs, here it says always use export router native tabs.
Okay.
So once again, I'll try to visualize it pretty quickly.
When you start a new session with AI, you're asking a question, right?
And then you are getting a result.
Let's say you just say build me authentication, and then it builds it. You say build me profile page, and then you get the end result.
But at the beginning, there is agents.md that is automatically loaded to the context.
This is what we explained.
Okay, so I hope now we understand the agents.md file and what's the difference between them.
Now what I have done off camera is going into VS Code and then I just said now go ahead and implement the account deletion when we press this delete account button.
Here it says you need to add the clerk secret sorry, clerk secret key to the dashboard.
This is what I have done. I just went into my project, settings, environment variables, and then just get the clerk secret key and paste it right here.
Now, how do you get this value?
Well, you can go into clerk export documentation.
So from here, let's just find
the environment variables.
Just select your project, and then you can also press the API keys by the way.
So here you have the publishable key, but we need the secret key as well.
So it is right here. Just go ahead and copy this value
and paste it right here.
So you can just say add and paste this value, it should be right here.
Then save.
This is exactly what I have done. I said I have added it.
So I said that's done. Go ahead and implement it. Now looks like this has been implemented. I'll say delete the account.
If I say cancel, nothing happens, but if I say delete, it should actually delete the account and sign me out.
Let's go ahead take a look at the dashboard.
Okay, so previously we had two different users, but now we have only one.
Alright, so I think with this, I'm gonna leave this section right here.
In the next section, we can build that privacy policy in terms of services.
And again, for this I have some pre-made prompts that I'll share with you. But for now, I think if you wanted to, you can pause the video and improve the UI as much as you want.
But I don't want to waste any time. Um I'll just go ahead and let's close everything.
And I'll just commit my changes.
So let's stage and get a commit message.
And I'll sync this up.
Okay, so with this, I'll see you in the next lesson.
Alright, now let's say you build your application, and it is time to get started with the legal pages.
Like what you need to do is pretty simple, and here I'll just try to walk you through it.
So, first off, let's talk about some of the must-have features that you should have.
One of them was the delete account button, which is something that we have implemented.
The other one is the Apple sign-in option.
Again, it is right here. This is basically something that you have to have if you included any other different social login options.
So in our case, we have Google, then Apple says you must have sign in with Apple option as well. Now, on top of privacy policy and terms of services, we also need to add a support URL.
This is something that Apple will ask you when you go into the Apple dashboard.
Okay, so I'll try to explain it
in a whole bit.
Okay, so with that in mind, now let's go ahead and create the privacy policy, terms of services, and a support URL.
And in the past, for one of my past tutorials, I have built a landing page like this, where we have some demo images
that is looking pretty cool, and we have like more details, and now I'll just show you how we can generate these type of mockups in like less than five minutes.
Okay, so with this in mind, on top of this, I'll provide you a terms of services prompt.
You can find this, just go ahead and copy it, and we'll go into codex.
Let me just create a new session.
Now, okay, so this is something I'll just delete.
I don't know why, but in the past, looks like I have it. So I just deleted that. And here I'll paste this in.
What this does is basically it says go ahead and read my entire codebase, and depending on my project, create me a terms of services page,
right?
And here I'll say
Um, like put everything under a folder called legal.
Let's actually create that. So I'll say
put it all under the legal folder and actually build me a landing page
as well.
Let's say make sure it looks pretty good.
Now, of course, this is not the best prompt, but I just want to see what it can give us in the first try, and then we can always follow up and add some references.
Now, before I run this prompt, what I'd like to do is actually preparing these demo images.
So for this, there is a website called shots.so, which is completely free to get started with.
They have paid plan as well, but you don't really need to pay just to create these images.
Okay, so head over to this site.
Here I'll just say start over.
This is what you're gonna see initially.
From here, go ahead and select a mock-up.
In this case, I'll just get iPhone 17, I believe.
You can select anything really.
I'll just get this one.
And then I'll say,
let me go under the frame. I'll say there should be no background.
Because here we would like to have a transparent background, right?
Like this doesn't have any white background, red background, nothing.
It should be transparent, and then for the images, for the images, you would like to open up your simulator and take a screenshot.
Then I'll just copy this.
Let's say copy the clipboard.
Here I'll press control V.
Okay, so I just pasted that.
Now you can get
this type of variation, but then you need the second image or even like three different images.
Let me just try to kind of like log in.
Because I'm going to get more screenshots.
Here I'll say continue and
okay. So I just logged in. Let's go under the explore screen and I'm going to take another screenshot.
Again, I'll copy this to clipboard.
Let's go and maybe create this one initially.
So I'm going to paste this in.
And what you'd like to do is zoom in as much as possible.
So you are basically deleting this extra space from the top and from the bottom.
So go ahead and zoom in. Don't make it this much, but just make sure that
you know you get rid of these extra spaces as much as possible.
So I'm gonna go ahead zoom in.
I think this is fine.
And you also want to make sure that under the mock-up you say there is no shadow, okay? Because if you have shadow, like let me select one of them.
Like I think it is not really that visible, but there is some shadow right here, and it's not gonna make it look like this if you have shadow.
Like, just trust me, go ahead and he'll like to select no shadow, and then we can export this.
So that's the first variation.
Let's go and get one of these.
I'll just keep it simple and get the first one.
Again, I'm zooming in as much as possible.
I'm going to export this as well, and let's go ahead and get one of these.
Yeah, I think I'll just go with this one.
Let me take a screenshot
maybe from the messages.
I'll copy it to clipboard.
Again, I'll paste this in.
Let's zoom in as much as possible.
Okay, so what we have just done here is something that you can implement in all of your future projects.
Just visit the site and do the same thing that I've done.
Now I'm gonna get these three images and I'll just paste it into VS Code.
Let's actually go under the legal folder. I'm gonna drag and drop.
And let's just say
like I'll rename it. I'll say demo one.
Um I think this should be
demo three, sorry, demo two and three.
Now I will go into codex.
So I had this prompt and I'll just say in landing page, use
these images,
which are demo one,
two, and three.
Okay, so I'll just run this and let's see what we're gonna get back.
all right so this took around 17 minutes.
GPT not only build it but also test it out on the browser.
So here you can tell I have a bunch of different files, but the important one is the index.html. Just go ahead, right click, and then open this with the live server.
If you cannot see this option, then just head over to the extensions and just get the live server extension.
Let me show you that pretty quickly.
It's gonna be this one, install it, and then you should be able to see it.
So right-click, press this, and here we go. This is the end result, and I think UI is way better than what I expected, and like we didn't give any kind of reference at all.
It has built it by itself, and notice how it is following the system design that we currently have.
So it didn't build something like in the red color or purple or really anything, but instead it like it is following the blue color theme that we have in the mobile application.
Now, if you wanted to, you can of course, as usual, you can follow up and improve the design.
I don't want to waste any time, but here you can tell we have the terms of services under the terms endpoint or URL, I would say.
Now, here you can tell there are a bunch of different placeholder fields.
That's because AI cannot really guess what is the legal name of your business, you know, privacy policy URL, things like that,
because this is still not deployed. So these are some um placeholders that you would like to actually read and fix. But other than these, you don't really need to change anything else.
This is exactly what I have done when I was building my own mobile application, and I think like this is the old name.
sorry, this is the old name.
Previously it was called Bulky AI, but recently I have updated the name, but it is still under the old domain, which is fine.
So here I have the terms of services. If you
if you scroll to the bottom, here you can tell.
Like I just put the details about my business, you know, where I'm from, things like that.
And now it's time to build the privacy policy.
And for this, again, I have the prompt.
You'll just go ahead get this entire thing.
Let's paste this in.
And now it should also build the privacy policy.
Once this is done, I'll just be right back.
Alright, so after some time, this has also been implemented. Here you can tell in the footer we have this link.
Again, there are a bunch of different placeholders that you would like to read and update just before you publish your app to the app store, and then you would like to kind of like
deploy this because currently this is running on your local machine.
Now I'll show you how to deploy it in a second, but first let's go back to our list.
Now we have built the privacy policy in terms of services.
On top of this, you also want to have a support URL because this is a field that Apple will ask you in the Apple dashboard when you want to deploy it.
And this is gonna be by the way under the Apple Store Connect.
So we can actually visit that, like App Store Connect. Sorry, not Apple Store, it should be App Store Connect.
So, this is something that I go into in detail in my school community, but basically, in simple terms, this is going to be the place where you will publish your app.
And they ask for a support URL.
Now let's go ahead and build it as well. I'll just say also add a support page.
Please keep it simple and super quick to build.
Like I don't want to wait 10 minutes.
So I'll just say don't test only build.
Now usually I wouldn't say this, but this uh this is just because this is a tutorial, I'll say don't test it, just build so that we don't waste any time.
And now while this is building, let's go ahead and see Cloudflare.
This is where we will deploy our application.
Sorry, this is where we will deploy our privacy policy and in general the landing page. So this is completely free to get started with.
Just go ahead and sign up with your GitHub account.
This is what I have done, and you'll just go into VS Code under Codex, Cloud, whatever you're using, you will just say go ahead and deploy this to Cloudflare pages.
Okay, and looks like support page has been completed.
Let me double check.
We have the support page. Here, the only thing that you need to update is the support email, which is something pretty easy to do.
If you don't know how to do it, just talk with Codex,
basically it'll walk you through the entire process. Okay, so with that said, what you'd like to do for deployment, just going here and saying something like deploy the
legal folder, right?
So we have the legal folder, I'll just say deploy this to Cloudflare
pages.
And Cloudflare has a tool called Wrangler, which is a CLI tool that allows you to publish your app without touching the browser.
So from the terminal, it can use this tool and deploy your app. So I'll just say use Wrangler, and I already
have the setup and login.
If you don't have, you can say go ahead and set this up for me, or just tell me the process how I can set this up.
Okay, so I'm gonna run this, and after I believe a couple of minutes, this should be deployed.
Alright, so it was super quick. Here you can tell it took one minute and 20 seconds, and if you press the link, here you can tell our landing page is live.
Now we can use this URL in the App Store Connect dashboard.
So you can add this link as your privacy policy, this link for the terms of services, and then
slash support. Let me just find it.
This for the support URL.
Alright, so this is how you build the illegal pages and deploy it to internet.
The only thing left for you to do is filling filling in these placeholders, and literally that's it.
Now with that, I think I'm gonna leave this lesson right here.
Let's go ahead and visit VS Code.
And as usual, we're gonna stage everything and commit our changes.
Alright, so this is where we left. Now in this section, I'd like to talk about something called error tracking and monitoring, which sounds pretty complex, but it's actually pretty easy to implement.
And it's really, really important to understand, especially if you are building apps.
For us to be able to understand it, first we need to see the problem and then the solution.
Then I'll show you how to integrate it.
So let's just see the problem first.
Now let's say you built your own application, right?
You deploy it to App Store, everything is working in your own device and even in the simulator.
But you cannot really just assume that this is gonna work for every single one of your users.
Now, like it or don't like it, in real applications, there are always some kind of edge cases, and like there will always be some problems that you need to fix.
And now you need to be notified anytime your users are getting some errors.
Now let's take a look at the diagrams that I have prepared.
So here, you know, like what happens when your users face some errors?
Do you think they will send you an email or do you think they will delete the application and leave a one-star review with a really bad comment?
Well, 99% of the time this is what's gonna happen because they don't even know who you are, right?
So how would they know your email?
So they'll never try to send you an email explaining the issue. They'll just delete the app, leave a one-star review, and they'll say something like, I don't know, like profile screen doesn't work.
I'm trying to see my profile image, but it is not even visible.
I am deleting this app, something like that, right?
So that's the problem that you need to kind of fix.
Anytime there is an error, you need to get an email automatically seeing the error, the user, and how to fix it.
So that's the beauty of Sentry.
This is where Sentry comes in.
We're gonna fix it by using Sentry, which is completely free to get started with.
So think of it like the watchtower of your application.
Now it is much more than just error tracking and monitoring, but here are some of the things that I can highlight.
So it's going to catch the errors, it's going to show us the structured logs, which is like console.log, but it is structured, that means you know it is searchable and it is persisted in the cloud.
Then there are session replays, which means that it's gonna take video recording anytime there is an error.
So let's say your user presses button and it has failed.
So you will have the video recording of that in your sentry dashboard.
Then it helps with performance, such as traces and bottlenecks, and as I have already mentioned, you're going to get real-time alerts.
Now by default, it's gonna work with your email, but if you wanted to, you can set this up with Slack, I believe Discord and even Microsoft Teams.
Okay, so this is completely free to get started with.
If you use the link in the description, you're gonna get $80 extra free credits, which is pretty generous.
So go ahead and sign up with that link, and then you'll be in the sentry dashboard. So initially, probably you will not have any projects, so just go ahead and say create a project.
From here, you can select your repository.
Let's say you don't have a repository on GitHub, which is completely fine.
So this is optional, right?
then you would select your platform, in this case it's gonna be React Native, and then give it a project name, like anything, code X Gram.
This is what I'm gonna leave, and then we'll say create the project.
Now I'm gonna select my repository, and as soon as I select it, it is going to automatically detect that it is a React Native project.
So here I just search for my repository, I can select it, and now it's going to auto-detect that this is a React Native project.
I'll leave everything as it is, but I'll update the project name.
I'll say codex gram even though you can call it anything really.
Then you can also update the alert frequency. I'll just leave everything as default, and here you can tell you can connect it to Slack, Discord, and Microsoft Teams.
But for now I'll just leave it as email, which is pretty comfortable, especially if you're just building it by yourself.
Like if you don't have a team.
Okay, so with that said, now this is what you're gonna get, which is called Sentry Wizard.
Now you can run this automatically, sorry, by default, or you can just copy the instructions and paste it to AI.
Now, if you wanted to, again, you can just open up a new terminal, copy this entire thing and run it.
But I'll just get the instructions and I will paste it right here in my codex session.
So let me go ahead and open up a new chat.
And maybe I'll try to zoom in.
I'll paste this in, it explains everything, and it even provides the DSN, which is a connection string.
Basically, it'll allow us to connect to this specific project.
Anytime you create a new project, by the way, you'll get a different DSN.
Okay, so with this, I'll go ahead and run it.
This will set up Sentry, and then hopefully we should be able to test this out.
Now, while this is building it, there are a couple of different features of Sentry that I would recommend you to set up. Like the first one
is going to be sentry logs.
So let's just go ahead and say sentrylogs React Native.
I would visit the documentation and then I would just copy the entire page and ask, you know, Codex or Cloud, whatever you're using.
I'll just say set up Sentry logs for my project. And it is actually pretty simple.
It is just a one line change.
And like if you're interested, you can pause the video and read this documentation, which they explain everything in detail.
But let me try to pretty quickly go over it.
So to be able to understand what century logs is, here I have prepared this comparison between console.log versus sentry
logs. So here, as you already know, console.log lives on user's device only, right? So it's going to disappear when the application closes.
It is plain text and it has no connection to errors.
Like it is super simple for simple projects for debugging.
But on the other side, sentry logs are sent to sentry servers, which means it is saved on the cloud.
It is persisted and searchable.
That means you can you can literally query anything.
And to be able to query them, there are some tags.
So it is structured and it is linked to the traces, errors, and replays.
Now here's how to use it.
Like you can have different logs for debugging purposes, you know, just for information logs, warnings, errors, and even something like fatal,
which is you know really, really important and that is like kind of like a problem that needs to be fixed immediately.
So to give you an example, database connection failing is something fatal that you need to fix.
Okay, so you can just pause the video and read this if you're interested, which I would highly, highly recommend.
This is one of those things that people don't really care, but as a app owner, I think this is one of the most important topics.
So that like you can get the email and immediately solve it before your application has really bad reviewing.
Okay, so with this, let's take a look at the VS Code.
I think this is still
setting this up.
Once it is done, I'll just be right back.
Alright, so within the six minutes, this has been installed and set it up correctly.
Now, one thing that I want to mention is that Sentry is a native module. So once you install it or once you set this up, you need to rebuild your application.
So as you already know, rebuilding means you need to just say npx expo run iOS in your terminal, right?
So just copy this, kill your application from your terminal, which is this one, and then rerun it. And then your application will be live once again.
Now with this, I'm gonna go ahead and paste this into actually not this one, sorry.
I'm gonna get this copy page
um for sentry logs, and I'll just say go ahead and set up sentry logs.
Let's say this is dogs for sentry logs
set up for me.
Alright, so as you can tell that this has been set up pretty quickly in less than one minute.
Now on top of this, what I have asked is this I said go ahead and create me a sentry test page under the settings and create some errors and logs when we press those buttons.
So this is going to simulate real world issues so that I can see them in my sentry dashboard and explore.
So after two minutes, it was able to build this screen called Sentry Test.
And now we can press these buttons, which is going to create a bunch of different errors that kind of like simulate a real world implementation,
right?
Or a real real world use case, I would say.
Now let's go ahead and run some of them.
Like anytime you press them, they're gonna catch the errors, right?
It's going to throw an error and we're going to catch it with this entry.
So here I'll just press a couple of times.
And now let's go ahead and select our project.
In this case, it's going to be this one,
and go under the issues.
Like here you can tell, 10 seconds ago we got all these errors,
and at the same time, you're going to get the email in real time so that you can see what is going on, what is broken, and then you can jump into your code base and fix them.
Now, if you press any of them, you're going to get the whole details about the error, about the user, like what's the um
you know what's the operating system they're using, what is the device that they have, so on and so forth.
I'll just leave you to explore it. You can scroll to the bottom and basically check almost every single detail.
Then you can go under the explore and take a look at the logs as well.
Here you can tell there are a bunch of different logs that are generated.
And now, since in our project, we only have one user.
currently, you might not be able to see the importance of logs, but just imagine you have, like 1000 users or like even 10,000 users.
then logs will be really, really handy where you can basically debug everything about your project.
So, overall, that's the basics of sentry. This is how we can set this up, and there's also sentry tracing.
Let's double check.
I'll just say sentry tracing react native in the exact same way.
You can go ahead and copy this page, paste it into codex or cloud, whatever you're whatever you are using, and then it's going to set this up.
You can read what this is for, mostly for performance, and like this is something that I have set it up in my actual application.
Okay, so I'll just leave it as a challenge if you want to implement, and with this, I think we can commit our changes and leave this section right here.
Well, actually, I just realized there is one more component that I'd like to show you, which is going to be a feedback element.
So let's go ahead and search for sentry react native feedback.
So with this component, you can basically
you can basically get feedback from your users.
I'm just gonna go ahead and press this one.
So like this is what you will see, what your users will get, where they can add their full name, email, and you know the feature that they would request.
So I'm gonna go ahead, copy this entire page, and I'll just say
under the settings screen,
add a nice
feedback button
with sentry.
Once this is done, I'll just be right back.
So it took around two minutes, and here we go. Now, if you press this button, we got the component. Let's go ahead and add a you know, a suggestion or a feedback. I'll just give it my name.
Let's say this is my email.
I think
I need to copy it like this.
Let's just say hey please fix the profile screen.
Now in your sentry dashboard, if you visit issues and user feedback, you're gonna see that we got that feedback, right?
So we have the username, the detail, and if you press that, you'll be able to see everything else.
And if you cannot really find it at the time that you're watching this video, you can just go to the search bar and search for the user feedback.
Just press that and it's gonna take you to the screen.
all right so overall that's it for the Sentry integration.
There is one more thing that I want to do.
When we press these buttons, let's actually go ahead and link them to the actual URL, right? So I'm gonna say when we press privacy policy
in terms of services, link it to the actual deployed,
let's say URLs.
All right, so within the next one minute, this has been all right, So in one minute it's been implemented. Let's go ahead and press these.
As you can tell, it is taking us to the actual URL.
Now instead of opening opening this up in Safari, I'll just say, can you open this up within the app?
Like a sheet would come from the bottom and we would see the website.
So I'll just say so that was a super simple fix. As you can tell, when you press, now it just opens up within the app.
Same for the terms of services.
Okay, so I think that's it for the entire project, or at least for this section. Let's go ahead and commit everything.
I'll stage everything, let's get a commit message and then we're gonna commit this.
So this is my commit message, I'll commit and let's say sync this up.
Alright, so that's pretty much the entire application that we have built.
So from here on out, all you need to do is just going and talking with your AI agents so that they can improve the UI design.
I'm not gonna try to do it, even though I have tried to like off camera just make the homepage look a little bit more cleaner.
Here's my prompt.
But yeah, as I said, at this point you'd like to just have a couple of different follow-ups.
I don't know, maybe generate more design references and then ask them to kind of like implement it until you like the end result.
So with all that said, I think I'm gonna leave this tutorial right here. I hope you enjoyed it and learn something new from it.
If so, don't forget to like and subscribe, and hopefully, I'll see you in the next one.